Guide to the Elihu Club, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Elihu Club, Yale University, records
1791-1965
RU 882
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.75
469.33
The records consists of photocopies of the Yale Elihu Club constitution, by-laws, correspondence, and member lists, as well as an original print (1791) by Amos Doolittle.
Elihu (Society)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Existence and Location of Copies
A digital reproduction of the Amos Doolittle print, Accession 2005-A-200, can be found in the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Images Database (MADID). A link to MADID can be found on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were a gift of the Elihu Club, 2004. Accession 2005-A-200 on deposit by the Elihu Club, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of photocopies of the Yale Elihu Club constitution, by-laws, correspondence, and member lists, as well as an original print (1791?) by Amos Doolittle.
Biographical / Historical
The Elihu Club, a Yale senior society, was established in 1903.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Elihu (Society); Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students
- By-laws, constitution, correspondence, and member lists of the Elihu Club, 1903-1965; Accession 2001-A-180
  - Minutes
    - 1903-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 5)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Founding of Elihu" by Arthur B. Hooker; "The Purpose of Elihu"; "Recollections of Elihu: 1903-1963", Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Directory, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs [thumbnail gallery printouts of digital images], 2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    General
    See also: Elihu photo library digital images. Early 1900's, Sports, House Renovations, 2001
  - Elihu photo library digital images. Early 1900's, Sports, House Renovation, 2001; 71 computer files (JPEG)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
    - Elihu 6-1-01, 2001-a-180-0001; 1 (Box 3)
- "A Display of the United States," original engraved print by Amos Doolittle, [1791?]; Accession 2005-A-200
  Restricted deposit
  Scope and Contents
  Original engraved print by Amos Doolittle (New Haven, Conn.), featuring a Head-and-shoulders portrait of George Washington, "President of the United States of America. The protector of his country, and the supporter of the rights of mankind." Inter-looped circle of the Seal of the United States and 13 state seals encompass the portrait.
  - Print, 1791? (Box 1)